# Mark Ryan Guamos

Metro Manila



ryan.guamos@gmail.com



09178014376



linkedin.com/in/mark-ryan-guamos

# Summary

A Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of professional experience, specializing in fullstack development, Java, SQL, and Javascript. A proven track record of managing large scale software engineering projects to support cloud deployments and integrations.

## **Experience**



### Software Engineer

**Amihan Solutions** 

Jul 2022 - Present (7 months)

Helped with fixing bugs and adding features.

Participated in integrating with clients and third-party providers.

Provided application support for multiple clients.

Utilized AWS cloud services

#### Software Engineer

**Shang Software Solutions** 

Nov 2017 - Jun 2022 (4 years 8 months)

Improved existing applications and fixed concurrency issues.

Automated processes and regression tests using Selenium.

Developed monitoring tools.

Utilized DevOps tools like CI/CD, Docker, and Kubernetes

Developed several microservices.

Helped in migrating on-premise applications to Azure.



#### **Software Engineer**

Yondu, Inc.

Aug 2016 - Oct 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Helped with fixing bugs and SQL optimizations.

Mentored some developers on fullstack development.

Participated in the revamping of a legacy application.



#### **Software Engineer**

iServe Customer Management Solutions Inc.

Dec 2014 - Jul 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Led a small team of developers.

Developed a Case Management System for a gov't agency.

Mentored some junior developers.

# Java Developer

New World Solutions Ltd

Jan 2013 - Nov 2014 (1 year 11 months)

Helped with fixing bugs and adding features.

Assisted with QA testing.

# Java Developer

**ODGS** 

Jan 2012 - Jan 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Helped with fixing bugs and provided application support.

# Java Developer

**AATi Technologies** 

Nov 2010 - Sep 2011 (11 months)

Helped with small bug fixes while learning Java and several Java frameworks.

Developed a small tool that parses handwritten values in a scanned form using OCR.

#### **Education**

# International Electronics and Technical Institue

IT, IT 2006 - 2010

#### **Skills**

Java • Spring Framework • Spring Boot • Hibernate • JavaScript • SQL • React.js • Angular • Blockchain